m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯：冰藍 小雷_Amber 二川 珞珞 卜小早 小泓泓 拉圖
時間軸：MH 擱淺 雪貴人   后期：MythCreator
校對：圈圈 青椒  總監:  蘋果果
我的名字叫奧利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地獄一般的小島上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回來只有一個目標
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
to save my city.
但要達到目標  我不能像過去一樣成為兇手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
為了紀念我的朋友  我只能偽裝成另一個人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
深切懷念托馬斯·梅林
孝子
成為另一個存在
I must be something else.
《綠箭》前情回顧
Previously on "Arrow"...
我是巴里·阿倫  來自中心城市警局
I'm Barry Allen, from the Central City Police Department.
是犯罪現場調查組的工作人員
I'm with the Crime Scene Investigation Unit.
我有朋友能夠幫我
I have friends that can help.
-這奇跡可能會殺死你  -動手吧
- This miracle could kill you. - Do it.
一種用來制造人體武器的血清
It was a serum designed to create human weapons.
你覺得有人找到了配方
You think someone found the recipe?
離心機和血庫被盜
A centrifuge and a large supply of blood.
我覺得有人想要生產更多的血清
I think someone wants to make more of it.
-奧利弗  -他還活著嗎
- Oliver! - Is he alive?
-費利西蒂  我們救不了他  -對  我們救不了
- Felicity, we can't save him! - I know. We can't.
求你救救我朋友
Please save my friend.
按住他
Hold him!
他沒法活下來了
He's not going to make it.
他會活下來的  只要找到他體內有什么
He will. We just have to find out what's in his system.
一般我只處理死人
I--I--I usually only work on dead people.
-巴里  -好  他的身體做出這樣的反應
- Barry! - All right, I can think of four possible diagnosis
我能想到四種可能的診斷
for what's causing his body to react this way.
現在只有三種可能的診斷了
Make that three possible diagnosis.
兩種
Two.
開始胸部按壓
Start chest compressions.
我要抽血檢查
I need to get to his arm.
好了
Got it.
-他的靜脈正在內凝結  -什么
- He's suffering from intravenous coagulation. - What?
血液里有異常腫塊  就像楓糖漿一樣
His blood is unnaturally clotting. It's like maple syrup.
你能救他  對吧
You can save him, right?
對
Right.
殺鼠靈
幸虧你們這里老鼠成災
Lucky you guys have a rat problem.
你開玩笑嘛  那東西有毒
Are you kidding? That'll kill him!
如果我不這樣做  他就會死
He dies if I don't.
-費利西蒂  -動手吧
- Felicity... - Do it!
一定量的老鼠藥會稀釋他的血液
Just the right amount of this stuff will thin his blood enough
讓其重新循環
to get it circulating again.
放棄吧  奧利弗
Let go, Oliver.
他在衰弱
He's crashing.
別再掙扎了
Don't fight anymore.
奧利弗  保持清醒
Oliver, stay with me!
跟我走吧
Stay with me.
綠箭
第二季第九集
-奧利弗  放開他  -奧利弗
- Oliver, let him go. - Oliver!
出什么事了
What the hell is going on?
你被注射了一種強效凝血劑
You were injected with a strong-acting blood coagulant.
你本來快死了
You would have stroked out,
但幸運的是  你們這里有十分有效的血液稀釋劑
but fortunately you had a very effective blood thinner handy.
華法令阻凝劑
Warfarin.
又叫殺鼠靈
Better known as rat poison.
他救了你的命  奧利弗
Kid saved your life, Oliver.
按照救生事件的情節發展
This is the point in a lifesaving emergency
你現在應該感謝救命恩人
where you thank the person that did the lifesaving.
-你把我的身份告訴了他  -對
- You told him who I am. - Yeah, I did.
這秘密輪不到你來泄露  費利西蒂
That's not your secret to tell, Felicity.
由我來決定誰能知曉我的身份
I decide who finds out my identity.
我們沒時間等你投票
Well, we didn't have time to get your vote,
你當時昏迷不醒  即將死去
what with you unconscious and dying.
如果他離開這里  然后直接去找警察怎么辦
What happens if he leaves here and goes right to the police?
-他不會那樣做的  -我不會那樣做的
- He wouldn't do that. - I wouldn't do that.
-我信任他  -我不信
- I trust him. - I don't!
你打算怎么辦  朝他射箭嗎
What are you going to do, put an arrow in him?
-我在考慮  -別擔心  他開玩笑的
- I am considering it. - Don't worry, he's kidding!
你媽媽開槍打了你  你不是也來找我幫忙了嗎
How is this any different from when your mother shot you and you came to me for help?
你媽媽居然開槍打你
Your mother shot you?
狄格中了箭毒  你不是也把他帶來了這里嗎
Or when you brought Dig down here when he was poisoned with curare.
區別在于我調查過你們兩個
The difference is that I did my homework on both of you!
我從來不會隨便告訴別人
I don't just tell people easily.
我不會告訴別人的
I'm not going to tell anyone.
你沒必要感謝我
And you don't have to thank me,
但你該感謝她  別這么混蛋好嗎
but you should thank her instead of being kind of a jerk.
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.
來自媽媽
你能回家嗎
我得回家了
I have to go home.
我在避難室里與之搏斗的男人
That man that I fought in the bunker,
他有能力批量生產島上的血清
he has what he needs to mass produce the serum from the island.
我們得阻止他
And we have to stop him.
他抓住你脖子時  碰了你的皮膚
He touched your skin when he grabbed your neck.
我吸取了他皮膚中的殘油
I was able to absorb the residual oils from his skin,
將其放入凝膠聚合物中
which, when added to a gel-based polymer,
也許能夠重建他的指紋
might be able to recreate his fingerprint.
與偶像見面后總是會幻滅  對吧
Never meet your heroes, right?
媽媽
Mom?
謝謝你回家來  親愛的
Thank you for coming home, sweetheart.
發生什么事了嗎
Is everything all right?
我不知道  你妹妹把自己鎖在房里
Well, I don't know. Your sister has locked herself in her room
不肯和我說話
and she won't talk to me.
-別擔心  我和她談談  -好
- Don't worry, I'll talk to her. - Ok.
今天是圣誕節啊
It's Christmas.
是的
Yes.
但考慮到我們最近舉辦的盛會
But given the last gala that we threw,
今年還是不要舉辦圣誕派對了
I think we're going to skip this year's Christmas party.
西婭  我是奧利  開門
Thea, it's Ollie. Open the door.
現在不行  奧利
Not--not now, Ollie.
閃電妞  快開門
Speedy, open the door!
媽媽和你一起來了嗎
Is mom with you?
沒有
No!
發生什么事了
What's going on?
-我不想讓媽媽看到  -看到什么
- I didn't want mom to see. - See what?
他怎么了
What happened to him?
他做了治安維持者的靶子
Vigilante decided to use him as target practice.
你是對的
You're right--
那人是個瘋子
the guy's a psycho.
你為什么不去醫院
Why didn't you go to the hospital?
在這座城市
In this city,
中箭會像中槍一樣引來警方的注意
an arrow's the same as a bullet if you want the cops involved.
雖然媽媽挺喜歡羅伊的
And mom actually likes Roy,
但要是她發現他和兜帽男糾纏不清
but something tells me she'd revoke his tree trimming invitation
她一定不會讓他裝飾圣誕樹了
if she found out he was messing around with the hood.
羅伊
Roy.
會很疼的
This is going to hurt.
我的憤怒能沖淡疼痛
My anger's dulling the pain.
這個能沖得更淡
This will dull it better.
然后用力按住  就這樣
Going to put pressure on it. Right there.
狄格爾  我需要你來一趟奎恩宅邸
Diggle, I need you to come to the Queen mansion.
羅伊被射中了
Roy's been shot.
中的是箭
With an arrow.
說來話長
It's a long story.
先把急救箱拿來西婭的房間
Look, just bring the first aid kit to Thea's room.
謝謝
Thank you.
羅伊  我的司機狄格爾先生
Roy, my driver, Mr. Diggle,
在部隊的時候受過醫療訓練
he has medical training from his time in the army.
-他會幫你包扎  -謝謝
- He's going to patch you up. - Thank you.
不過是盡我所能
It's the least I can do.
我不知道你們三個想干什么
Look, I don't know what the three of you are up to,
但也許治安維持者只是想保證你們的安全
but maybe the vigilante was just trying to keep you safe.
所以他才射了羅伊嗎
By shooting Roy?
我只是猜測
I... i'm just saying.
也許你們應該放手
Maybe you should let this go.
所以  你會放手嗎
So... are you going to let this go?
不
No.
但現在起一切聽我的
But now we're going to do things my way.
媽媽
Mom!
有人嗎
Hello!
你好  我的愛人
Hello, my love.
莎朵
Shado?
你不可能是真的
You can't be here.
我必須來見你
I had to see you.
-我得警告你  -警告我
- Had to warn you. - Warn me?
你無法抵抗接下來要發生的事
You can't fight what's coming.
放下你的弓
Put down your bow.
脫下我父親的兜帽
Take off my father's hood.
我戴兜帽是為了紀念你父親
I wear that hood to honor your father.
也為了紀念你
And to honor you.
如果你想紀念我
If you want to honor me,
停止爭斗  好好生活
stop fighting...and live.
不然所有你愛的人都會死
Or everyone you love will die.
奧利
Ollie?
你剛剛在和誰講話
Who were you talking to?
放下武器
Put off your weapons.
滾過去
Get over there!
奇跡
Mirakuru.
把他們帶走
Take them.
安東尼
Anthony...
你已經得償所愿了
you got what you wanted.
你可以放了他們
You can let them go.
要是你真正在乎過我
If you ever cared about me.
我確實在乎你  莎拉
But I do care about you, Sara.
所以我不會選擇殺你
Which is why I won't choose to kill you.
但是他可能會
But he might.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
是時候做出選擇了  奧利弗
Time to choose, Oliver.
選出誰生  誰死
Who lives, and who dies.
不過你得選快點  因為30秒后
But pick quickly, because in 30 seconds,
我會把她們都殺了
I will shoot them both.
孵化已經開始了
The incubation process has begun.
48小時后就可以散播血清
Serum will be ready for distribution in 48 hours.
只要兩天
Two days.
我們就能創造上百個像你一樣的人
And we will be able to create a hundred more like you.
這座城市的掌權人
And the people who run this city
終于能見識到真正的力量了
will see what real power looks like.
我就知道治安維持者有同伙
I knew the vigilante had partners.
他現在比較喜歡綠箭俠這個稱呼
He likes to be called the Arrow now.
你們三個和一些真正的人渣較量過
You three have messed with some really nasty people.
娃娃制造者  迷魂伯爵
The Doll Maker, Count Vertigo,
幕后者還有女殺手
Dodger, the Huntress.
我們沒有記錄在案
We weren't keeping score.
我記著呢
I was.
巴里
Barry.
你給我用的老鼠藥  有沒有副作用
The rat poison that you gave me... are there any side effects?
有  可能出現幻覺
Um, yeah, I think hallucinations, maybe.
以及大量出汗
And excessive sweating.
你有沒有出很多汗
Are you sweating excessively?
你產生幻覺了嗎
You're hallucinating?
你看到什么了
What are you seeing?
一個叫莎朵的女孩  和我一起在島上待過
A girl named Shado that was with me on the island.
莎朵
Shado.
莎拉
Sara.
你和多少女人一起被困島上
How many women were you marooned with?
你確定那個島不是虛構嗎
Are you sure this wasn't fantasy island?
你果然是在森林或者叢林里接受的訓練
You did train in a jungle or forest environment,
所以才選了綠色
hence the green.
讓我抽點血  看看怎么樣了
Hey, let me draw some blood, see what's up.
我能問你個事嗎
Hey, can I ask you something?
為什么不戴面具
Why no mask?
我不是想教你該怎么去維持治安
Not to tell you how to do your vigilante...ing,
只是涂油彩
but the grease paint thing?
不是個隱藏身份的好辦法
It's a poor identity concealer.
那你去幫我找個既能完美適合我的臉型
So find me a mask that conforms perfectly to my face
在我奔跑的同時又完全不妨礙到瞄準力的面具
and doesn't affect my ability to aim while I'm on the run.
你可以試試可壓縮的超細纖維
You should look into a compressible micro fabric.
-會非常好用的  -發現塞勒斯·戈爾德
- It could be great. - Found Cyrus Gold.
塞勒斯·戈爾德是誰
Who's Gyrus Gold?
那天晚上差點把你弄死的那個人體武器
The human weapon that left you nearly dead the other night.
那家伙從你脖子上取下了他的指紋
The kid did manage to pull his print off your neck.
我用人臉識別軟件
I've had facial recognition software
掃描全城的閉路式攝像機
scanning closed circuit cameras all over town.
他現在在德爾加多大街和第二十五大道處
He's at the corner of Delgado and 25th right now,
但是馬上要跟丟了
but we're just about to lose him.
那個十字路口上還有什么
What else is at that intersection?
停車場  超市  汽車旅館
A parking lot, a market, a motel.
很可能就是他的藏身之所
Could be where he's holed up.
-我來搞定  -奧利弗
- I got this. - Oliver...
這件事我來處理吧
Why don't let me handle this one?
只是偵察而已
It's just recon.
好吧
Fine.
我做你的后援
But I'm going as your back-up.
別擔心
Don't worry.
我會查出奧利弗到底怎么回事的
I'll figure out what's wrong with Oliver.
你盡早吧
You'd be the first.
需要議員陪你一起去做圣誕節采購嗎
神秘的愛慕者嗎
Secret admirer?
不是的  是我爸送來的
No, actually, they're from my father.
什么風把你吹來了
What brings you by?
我們需要你的幫助  辛迪的朋友被殺了
We need your help. Cindy's friend was murdered,
但是警方不肯介入調查
but the police aren't going to investigate.
說是吸毒過量致死  就這樣
They said that he ODed, end of story.
看看這個
Check this out.
他獻血賺外快
He earned extra money donating blood.
貧民區救災獻血活動
我們在馬克斯房間里找到的
We found it in Max's apartment.
如果他吸毒  他們不會要他的血  對吧
They wouldn't have accepted his blood if he was using, right?
馬克斯和獻血車同天消失的
Max went missing the same day as the blood drive.
如果他真的去那獻血了
If he did donate blood there,
至少他們會知道點馬克斯的情況吧
maybe they at least know something that happened to him.
我去打聽一下
I'll ask around.
謝謝你  勞蕾爾
Thank you, Laurel.
帕特麗夏飯店
如果無聊  儲備箱里有本填字游戲的書
If you get bored, I keep a book of crossword puzzles in the glove box.
這話一點都不好笑
That's not funny.
你看到什么了
Ok, what do you see?
房間很干凈
It's clean.
非常干凈
Really clean.
"所羅門·格蘭迪  周一出生..."
"Solomon Grundy, born on a Monday..."
周二洗禮
Christened on Tuesday.
我知道那首詩  象征著生命的七個階段
I know the poem. It symbolizes the seven stages of life--
從出生到死亡
From birth to death.
這家伙現在處于哪個階段
What stage is this guy in?
快走快走  快  快
Go, go, go, go, go!
他輕而易舉地就能把我拎起來
He picked me up like I was nothing.
-費利西蒂  請求支援  -馬上來
- Felicity, call for back-up.  - On it.
是莎拉的事嗎
This about Sara?
你有她的消息嗎
You heard from her?
沒有
No.
抱歉  這是...
I'm sorry, this is...
是別的事
This is something else.
塞勒斯·戈爾德
Cyrus Gold.
上周他到奎恩聯合企業的
He robbed the Applied Sciences division
應用科學部門偷了東西
of Queen Consolidated last week.
警探
Detective...
他是個危險分子
He's extremely dangerous.
從中心城市派來的現場調查員
The CSI kid from central city,
他說這人就像某種怪物
he said this guy was like some kind of monster.
確實是
He is.
是什么東西  用了類固醇嗎
Well, what is it, steroids?
更糟糕  是...
Worse. It's--
那個是...
It's...
好吧  就算我相信你  你為什么來找我
Well, assuming I believe you, why come to me?
我妥協了
I've been compromised.
什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是我現在是個累贅
It means I'd be a liability.
這事你必須相信我  警探
You have to take my word on this, detective.
盡可能召集多的人手
Gather as many men as you can,
能殺死塞勒斯·戈爾德的時候一定不要猶豫
and do not hesitate to kill Cyrus Gold.
因為如果他有機會
Because if given the opportunity,
他也會毫不猶豫地殺了你
he'll do the same to you.
你不需要這么做
You don't have to do this!
你拿到了你想要的東西
You got what you came for!
拿上東西走吧
Just take it and go!
還剩十秒
10 seconds.
你這變態的神經病
You freaking psychopath!
歷史自有決斷
History will make that judgment.
還剩五秒
Five seconds.
時間到
Time's up.
不  不
No, no!
我想你已經做出了選擇
I guess you made your choice.
不
No!
你來這里干什么
What are you doing here?
我是來找西婭的
I came by to see Thea.
進來吧
Go on in.
她在樓上她的房間里
She's upstairs in her room.
我開車過來的時候注意到
I noticed on the drive up that your house
你們家沒有布置圣誕裝飾
wasn't festooned with Christmas decorations.
我們今年不是
Well, we didn't feel very much like
很想布置
festooning this year.
我知道你的意思
I know what you mean.
我記得去年圣誕節
I remember last Christmas,
湯米和我來參加你們的聚會
Tommy and I came here for your party.
那是我很長時間以來過的最好的節日
It was one of the best holidays I'd had in a really long time.
我該去找西婭了
Anyway, I should probably go talk to Thea.
我調查了獻血活動
I checked into the blood drive,
是完全合法的
and it's all legitimate.
實際上  塞巴斯蒂安的工作
In fact, what Sebastian's done
已經幫忙拯救了許多生命
has helped save a lot of lives.
如果獻血活動是合法有益的
So if the blood drive is on the up and up,
那我們該怎么找到殺馬克斯的兇手
then how are we supposed to find Max's killer?
還有一件事
There's one other thing.
所有參加活動的獻血者
All of the blood donors at the drive
都參加了蘭福德研究所的
were subjected to a psych evaluation
精神評估
by the Langford Institute.
那是合法的嗎
Is that, like, legal?
這并不是完全不合常理
It's not entirely out of the norm.
研究所的人
And while someone at the
應該知道馬克斯有沒有被下毒
institute might know if Max was on drugs,
貧民區救災獻血活動
沒有搜查令是沒法查出來的
There's no way of finding out without a warrant.
我們又沒法拿到搜查令
Which we're certainly not going to get.
很抱歉我只能幫到這里了
I'm sorry I couldn't be more help.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
只是隨便弄點東西
Uh, just messing around with something.
你不是應該在查奧利弗
Shouldn't you be trying to figure out
產生幻覺的原因嗎
what's causing Oliver's hallucinations?
樣本還在掃描  應該快好了
Sample's still being scanned. Shouldn't be too much longer.
很好
Good.
你真的很擔心他  對吧
You're really worried about him, huh?
他總是冒很大的險
He takes crazy chances.
即使是在他不幻想
Even when he's not hallucinating
島上那些漂亮姑娘的時候
about beautiful island girls.
那天晚上  我問你是不是喜歡奧利弗
The other night, I asked you if you liked Oliver.
我跟你說了  我不喜歡
I told you. I don't.
我記得
I remember.
但如果你喜歡...
But if you did...
我能看出原因
I could see why.
我是說  奧利弗·奎因
I mean, Oliver Queen.
白天他是個百萬富翁
He is a billionaire by day
晚上他拯救城市
and saves the city by night.
聽起來你想跟他約會啊
Sounds like you want to date him.
我是剛剛開始喜歡一個
I just have a little experience with liking someone
用不同于他人的眼光看我的人
who doesn't see you the same way.
今晚粒子加速器的啟動進入倒計時
Protests continue into the final countdown
對尖端科技研究實驗室頗具爭議的
for tonight's ignition of S.T.A.R.
抗議活動還在繼續
Lab's controversial particle accelerator.
尖端科技研究實驗室的創始人哈里森·威爾斯
S.T.A.R. Lab's founder Harrison Wells promises a new era
硬粒子加速器開啟倒計時
聲稱科技進步的新紀元即將到來
of scientific advancement is at hand.
我想我來不及回去看他們開啟加速器了
I guess I won't be back in time to see them turn it on.
我知道  是聽起來很瘋狂
I know, it sounds crazy.
人體武器
Human weapons?
他的名字叫塞勒斯·戈爾德
Look, his name is Cyrus Gold.
他就是上周闖入奎恩聯合企業的人
He's the one that broke into Queen Consolidated last week.
就是他搶了血庫
He's the one that robbed the blood bank.
也是他殺了那些人
And he killed all those people.
等等
Wait, hold on a second.
你怎么知道這些的
Where are you getting all this intel?
伙計  你是怎么了
Oh, man, what's a matter with you?
你就是因為跟治安維持者聯系而降職的
Talking to Wigilante's what got you demoted in the first place.
聽著  我們帶一支小隊去
Look, we take a small squad.
特警隊的麥卡西和埃文斯  還有瓊斯
Mccarthy and Evans from SWAT, Jones.
我們可以抓住這個家伙的
We can bring this guy down.
我答應過珍妮帶她去圣誕采購
I promised Jeannie I'd take her Christmas shopping.
盧卡斯
Lucas.
拜托
Please.
好吧
Fine.
但你得給珍妮打電話告訴她
But you get to call Jeanie and tell her
我沒法帶她去購物了
I'm not taking her shopping.
長官
Hey, Sir.
我不想越級
I don't mean to overstep,
但你能多帶一個人嗎
but could you guys use an extra man?
去穿件防彈衣  戴利警官
Grab a vest, Officer Daily.
警察盯上戈爾德了
The police are onto Gold.
他們在找他
They're looking for him.
我確信已經混進了隊伍
I made sure I'm in the loop.
現在絕對不能讓警察影響到我們
We are too close to let the police interfere.
塞拉斯兄弟
Brother Cyrus.
警察很想見你
The police are eager to meet you.
介紹一下你自己
Introduce yourself.
圣誕節有什么計劃嗎
So, any plans for Christmas?
點亮我的燭臺[猶太節日所用]
Lighting my menorah.
感覺怎么樣
Hi. How are you feeling?
還行
Fine. Just...
家里人多擁擠
It's a little bit crowded at my house,
我就想過來  一個人靜靜
and I wanted to come down here to get a little privacy.
沒問題
Yeah.
走吧  巴里
Come on, Barry.
去大胃王漢堡店看倒計時也行
We can watch the countdown at big belly burger.
你的血液分析快完成了
Your blood analysis is almost done.
謝謝
Thank you.
怎么了  小子
What's the matter, kid?
一臉看到鬼的樣子
You look like you've seen a ghost.
你確定他在里面嗎
Are you sure he's in there?
是的  長官
Yes, sir.
有人看到塞勒斯·戈爾德進去
Sector car spotted Cyrus Gold entering.
一直沒有出來
He hasn't left.
手槍保險都打開
Safeties off.
他在那邊  包圍過去
Over there. Surround him.
這地方不錯啊
This is a nice place.
比荒島上的破碎機艙
It's a bit more comfortable
稍微舒服點
than the fuselage on the island.
你不是真的
You're not real.
你也不是
Neither are you.
你對別人說  掀起這場變革
You told everyone when you started this crusade
是為了
that it was about
彌補你父親犯下的罪惡
making up for your father's sins.
真是謊話連篇
That was a lie.
你是為自己贖罪
This charade is to atone for your sins.
你已經死了
You're dead.
你不是什么英雄
You are not a hero.
也不配當朋友兄弟  你屁都不是
Or a friend. Or a brother. You are nothing.
不要背對著我[背叛我]
Do not turn your back on me,
第二次了
not again.
你已經去世了
You're gone.
不管我現在在哪...
Wherever I am...
你應該加入我
It's time you joined me.
莎翁說過懦夫一生千次死
They say a coward dies a thousand deaths.
可是你死一千次也不夠
But even that wouldn't be enough for you.
我試過救你
I tried to save you!
還有她
And her.
可你沒做到
But you couldn't.
正如你也救不了這座城市
Just like you couldn't save this city.
那座島根本沒讓你變強
The island didn't make you strong, kid.
反而暴露出你的軟弱
It revealed you to be weak.
謝謝你當我的購物指導
Thank you for being my shopping guide.
你還好嗎
Are you ok?
我沒事  那個
Uh, yeah, it's just, um,
我可以問你個問題嗎
can I ask you a question?
關于你發起的獻血活動
It's about the blood drive you sponsored.
當然  那是好事一樁
Of course. It's a wonderful cause.
尤其是對于那些資金不足的醫院來說
Especially with the underfunded hospitals we're dealing with.
怎么了
What about it?
喂
Hello?
什么
What?!
好的  我馬上過來
Ok, I'll be right over.
怎么了
What happened?
我爸爸
My father.
他受重傷住院了  抱歉
He's in the ICU. I'm so sorry.
非常抱歉  我得先走了
I'm so sorry, I have to go.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
發生什么事了
What happened in here?
有人闖進來過嗎
Did someone break in?
沒有
No.
你的血液分析結果出來了  好消息
Your blood analysis is done. Good news.
查到里面有什么了嗎
So you know what's in my system?
問題就在這里  你的血液很干凈
That's the thing-- your blood's clean.
沒有任何問題
There's nothing wrong with you.
那我為什么會產生幻覺
Then why am I hallucinating?!
我不知道
I don't know.
不管問題出在哪
But whatever your problem is,
肯定不是生理原因  而是心理問題
it's not pharmacological. It's psychological.
-是你的臆想  -是我的臆想
- It's in your head. - It's in my head.
老天
Oh, my god.
奧利弗
Oliver.
爸
Dad!
寶貝
Honey.
我的腳趾還能動  應該是個好跡象
Well, I can wiggle my toes, it must be a good sign.
我沒事  親愛的
I'm all right, honey, I'm fine.
盧卡斯怎么樣  他還好嗎
How's Lucas, is he all right?
對不起
I--I'm sorry.
你這是什么意思
What do you mean?
我得打電話告訴他妻子珍妮
I got to call Jeannie. I got to call his wife.
爸  你待著別動  我去打
No, dad, I'll do it. You just...stay here.
你好好休息
Get some rest.
你來這里干什么
What are you doing here?
來看看你爸爸有沒有事
Wanted to make sure your father was ok.
他沒事
He is.
順便也看看你還好嗎
I wanted to make sure you were, too.
你怎么樣  警探
How are you, detective?
沒死
I'm alive.
我的同伴就沒這么幸運了
Unlike most everyone else in my unit.
關于您搭檔的事我很遺憾
I'm sorry about your partner.
是我帶他進去的
I took him in there.
是因為我
Because of me.
我不想讓你失望
I hate to disappoint you,
但你沒必要對這城市的每樁命案負責
but not every death in this city is on you.
從戈爾德身上拿到的
I got this off Gold.
希望能幫到你
Hopefully you can do something with it.
開始我還不相信  但這個人
I didn't believe it at first, but this guy,
根本不像是人類
I mean, it's like he's not human.
他是人類
He's human.
那就殺了他
Well, then you can kill him.
為希爾頓  也為我
For Hilton. And me.
我覺得夠鋒利了
I think those are sharp enough.
很顯然我不這么認為
Apparently I'm not.
狄格爾  你覺得我是神經錯亂了嗎
Diggle, do you think I'm losing my mind?
沒比我們差多少
No more than the rest of us.
我看到
I saw...
斯萊德·威爾遜
Slade Wilson.
斯萊德是我在小島上的朋友
Slade was my friend on the island,
而且
and...
他和莎朵一樣  因我而死
like Shado, he is dead because of me.
蘭斯先生說
Mr. Lance just told me
我沒必要對這城市的每樁命案負責
that not every death in this city is my fault.
確實
Fine.
但確實有很多是我的責任
There are plenty that are.
當我從阿富汗回來時  我
When I got home from Afghanistan, I...
也看到了個鬼魂
saw a ghost, too.
幸存者的內疚
Survivor's guilt.
為什么我們獨活
Why us, not them.
我知道為什么
I know why.
那這"為什么"就不是你的問題
Then the "Why's" not your problem.
你是怎么趕走鬼魂的
How'd you make your ghost go away?
我明白了他們想告訴我的意思
I figured out what they were trying to tell me.
是什么
Which was?
那是說給我聽的  奧利弗
That's for me to hear, Oliver.
你得搞清你的那鬼魂想告訴你什么
You have to figure out what yours is trying to tell you.
伙計們  有新發現
Guys, we got something here.
我掃描了蘭斯給你的鑰匙
I scanned the key Lance gave you,
通過序列號查到了它的生產商
and traced its serial code back to the manufacturer.
這把鑰匙和貧民區新月環路某處
This particular key fits a locked gate
一個上鎖的門相匹配
somewhere on Crescent Circle in the glades.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
你這身體狀況不能隨便跑出去
You can't go out there in your condition.
我必須阻止他們
I have to stop this.
奧利弗  戈爾德沒直接把你打死
Oliver, Gold left you half dead,
比起希爾頓警探的遭遇可真是手下留情了
which is 50 percent better than how he left detective hilton.
費利西蒂
Felicity...
我別無選擇
I don't have a choice.
我會回來的
I'll come back.
你發誓
Promise me.
蘭福德研究所
馬克斯
Max.
米拉庫魯
萬事俱備
It's ready.
這就是你殺馬克斯·斯坦頓的地方嗎
Is this where you killed max stanton, hmm?
你要干嘛  敢用它扎我  我就殺了你
What are you doing? If you stick that in me, I'll kill you.
不  羅伊兄弟
No, Brother Roy.
你會為我殺人
You'll kill for me.
勒斯兄弟說他已經把你殺了
Brother Cyrus told me he killed you.
也許他沒你想得那么強大
Guess he's not as strong as you'd hoped.
你從哪里得到的米拉庫魯  誰給你的配方
Where'd you get the Mirakiru? Who gave you the formula?!
那是一件可以用來拯救這座城市的禮物
It was a gift. A gift I would use to save this city from itself.
另一件失敗品
Another failure.
站起來  奧利弗
Get up, Oliver.
湯米
Tommy?
你不能死在這里
You're not going to die down here.
湯米  對不起
Tommy, I'm sorry.
你是因我而死
I let you die.
我不是因你而死  奧利
You didn't let me die, Ollie.
你為了救我而戰
You fought to save me.
因為你就是這樣的人
Because that's what you do.
一如既往
What you have always done.
為生存而戰
You fight to survive.
我知道我曾叫你殺人犯
I know I called you a murderer,
但你不是
but you are not.
你是個英雄
You are a hero.
你戰勝了那座小島
You beat the island.
你戰勝了我父親
You beat my father.
戰斗下去  奧利弗
So fight, Oliver.
站起來
Get up,
以牙還牙
and fight back.
殺了他
Kill him.
我不會再眼睜睜看著別人死去
Hey. I am not leaving anyone else to die!
你很堅強  孩子
You're strong, kid.
加油  加油
Come on! Come on!
加油  羅伊
Come on, Roy!
戰勝它  加油  戰勝它
Fight. Come on, fight!
羅伊
Roy?!
Hey, Roy!
你去哪了  我到處找你
Where have you been? I've been looking all over for you!
我
I was...
我去追蹤一條線索
I was running down another lead.
似乎不太成功
It didn't pan out.
我還以為你又去找治安維持者了
I thought you were chasing after the vigilante again.
我嚇壞了  還以為你出什么事了
I got so scared. I thought something happened to you.
聽我說  別擔心
Hey, hey, don't worry.
我活得好好的
I'm alive.
我要為星城的人民大眾服務
I want to serve the people of Starling,
布拉德宣布參選市長
而不是為那些自以為擁有這城市的人
not the men and women who think they own it.
攜起手來  重建我們的城市
Together, we can help rebuild our city
不再有階級  不再有壓迫
into a place where there are no elites and no oppressed.
人人都是兄弟姐妹
Where we are all brothers and sisters.
看來你的競選開始了
So your campaign begins.
星城需要領袖
The city needs a leader.
讓冒牌兜帽男刺殺市長
And putting the copycat hoods up to assassinating the Mayor
只是第一步
was just the first step.
治安維持者
The vigilante...
他摧毀了離心機
He destroyed the centrifuge
也破壞了血清
and the serum along with it.
我會再給你提供一份我的血樣
I will arrange for you to receive another sample of my blood,
然后你就可以再次大批量制血清
and then you can begin to mass produce the serum again.
如果我不允許你與治安維持者對峙
When I ask you not to confront the vigilante,
你要聽令
you will listen.
記住  你的面具別人也可以戴
Remember, your mask can be worn by another.
你知道兜帽男是誰  對吧
You know who he is under that hood, don't you?
我再清楚不過了
I know exactly who he is.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
怪不得你不希望他死
That's why you don't want him dead.
死亡是一種解脫
Death would be a release from this life,
他還沒有接受審判
and his sentence is yet to be carried out.
我要摧毀他所在乎的一切
I am going to tear everything he cares about away from him.
制裁所有追隨他的人
Destroy those who choose to follow him.
蹂躪他至愛之人
Corrupt those he loves.
待他失去了
Once he has lost everyone
所有至親至愛
and everything he values...
我再用箭刺穿他的頭顱
I will drive an arrow through his eye.
莎朵
Shado...
Shado!
不
No!
為什么
Why?
我...
I...
艾沃開槍打死了她
Ivo just shot her.
不知道為什么
He didn't say why.
不管是誰做的
Whoever did this to her...
我要他血債血償
has got to suffer.
還有幻覺嗎
Still have a ghost problem?
沒有了
No.
我明白意思了
I got the message.
不過...
But we...
還有其他問題
We have other problems.
要沒問題就奇怪了
Wouldn't be us if we didn't.
羅伊被注射了血清
Roy was injected with the serum.
天啊  他怎么樣了
Oh, my god, is he ok?
還活著
He's alive.
不過我們得看著他
But we are going to have to keep an eye on him.
塞勒斯·戈爾德呢
And Cyrus Gold?
死于周六  周日安葬
Died on Saturday, buried on Sunday.
但他還有個同伙
But he was working with someone.
我看見他戴了一副面具
I saw him, he wore a mask
上邊畫著  骷髏
with the image of a...of a skull.
他想大批量生產血清  然后建立軍隊
He's trying to mass produce the serum to build an army.
為什么
For what?
你是一名軍人
You're a soldier.
軍隊的首要天職是什么
What's the primary purpose of an army?
戰爭
War.
巴里呢
Where's Barry?
他回中心城市了
He went back to Central City.
想及時趕回去
Wanted to get home in time
看他們打開粒子加速器
to see them turn on the particle accelerator.
我接個電話
I should take this.
到了嗎
Did you make it?
我及時趕回了中心城市
I made it back to Central City in time,
不過我很懷念尖端科研實驗室與世隔絕的生活
But I missed the cut off in line at S.T.A.R. Labs.
跟往常一樣  我遲到了
I was late, as usual.
但是我可不想再遲到了
But in spirit of not being late again,
你什么時候覺得
uh, if you ever decide that
奧利弗·奎恩不適合你
Oliver Queen isn't the guy for you;
或者覺得
if you decide that
想跟不一樣的人
you want to go on a date with
約會
someone else, um...
我想告訴你  那個人一定會準時的
You should know that that guy, he'll be on time.
很好
Good to know.
我給奧利弗留了個東西
Oh, hey, and I left something for Oliver.
希望他會喜歡
I hope he likes it.
再見  巴里
Bye, Barry.
再見  費利西蒂
Bye, Felicity.
我是琳達·帕克
I'm Linda Park
尖端科研實驗室外現場直播
and we're live outside S.T.A.R. Labs
天氣狀況十分惡劣  并且有惡化傾向
Despite the inclement weather, which is only going to get worse.
瓢潑大雨趕走了幾乎所有抗議者
The torrential downpour has driven away almost all the protesters
尖端科研實驗室總裁哈里森·威爾斯向我們保證
though S.T.A.R. Labs CEO Harrison Wells has assured us
今晚的風暴
that the storm tonight will
絕不會影響到粒子加速器
in no way affect the particle accelerator,
目前其運轉一切正常
which is up and running smoothly.
醫生被指控謀殺妻子
諾拉·艾倫死亡
諾拉·艾倫被其丈夫謀殺
我們現在被告知緊急疏散
Wait, we are now being told to evacuate the facility.
風暴可能使主冷卻系統
the storm may have caused a malfunction
發生了故障
to the primary cooling system.
工作人員正在試圖關掉粒子加速器
Officials are now trying to shut down the particle accelerator,
粒子加速器已打開
但是目前仍然無法重新控制系統
but so far have been unable to regain control of the system.
連綠箭俠也有圣誕禮物
Even the Arrow deserves a Christmas present.
戴上
Here.
怎么樣
How do I look?
像英雄
Like a hero.